<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" 
    xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
    xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
    xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
    xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
	<channel>
<title>My RSS Feed</title><link>https://intel-csu.github.io/index.html</link><description>Hot News&#x21;</description><dc:language>en</dc:language><language>en</language><dc:date>2023-04-03T09:53:00-04:00</dc:date><admin:generatorAgent rdf:resource="http://www.realmacsoftware.com/" />
<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
<sy:updateBase>2000-01-01T12:00+00:00</sy:updateBase>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 4 Apr 2023 01:12:25 -0400</lastBuildDate><item><title>Intel Ohio Team Visits CSU: A Day of Learning and Collaboration</title><dc:subject>Blog</dc:subject><dc:date>2023-04-03T10:21:00-04:00</dc:date><link>https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Intel_Ohio.html#unique-entry-id-9</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Intel_Ohio.html#unique-entry-id-9</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="imageStyle" alt="visit1" src="https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/visit1.jpg" width="4028" height="2116" /><br /></p><p style="text-align:left;">On Monday, April 3, 2023, the Intel Ohio team visited the campus of CSU to share their expertise and explore potential partnerships. The day was filled with opportunities for learning and collaboration, and both the Intel team and the CSU community gained valuable insights.<br />The visit by the Intel Ohio team started with a tour of the CSU campus and the educational and research labs and facilities. After the tour, the Intel team joined CSU's President, Dr. Thomas, for lunch. During the lunch, Dr. Hadizadeh, the lead PI of the Intel project at CSU, furnished an update on the progress and current status of the project. Dr. Kuti also provided valuable information on the areas where more investments can help expand CSU's semiconductor program, mainly supporting workforce development from underrepresented minorities.<br /></p><p style="text-align:center;"><img class="imageStyle" alt="visit2" src="https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/visit2.jpg" width="3989" height="2504" /><br /></p><p style="text-align:left;">The highlight of the visit was the informational presentation by VP Jim Evers, Intel's Ohio site manufacturing and operations manager. Jim shared insights on the latest technological advancements, future projects, and opportunities at the Intel Ohio factory. The presentation was informative and engaging, and it gave CSU faculty and students a glimpse into the world of semiconductors. He also offered CSU students information on job opportunities in the Intel Ohio factory. This was an exciting moment for the students, who were thrilled at the prospect of working for one of the top semiconductor companies in the world.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>CSU Intel Team Welcomes Dr. Khan as a Research Assistant Professor of Electronic Engineering Technology</title><dc:subject>Blog</dc:subject><dc:date>2023-04-03T09:53:00-04:00</dc:date><link>https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Khan.html#unique-entry-id-10</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Khan.html#unique-entry-id-10</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="imageStyle" alt="Mubbashar Altaf Khan" src="https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/mubbashar-altaf-khan.jpg" width="200" height="238" /><br /></p><p style="text-align:left;">Dr. Khan has joined the CSU Intel team as a Research Assistant Professor of Electronic Engineering Technology. They were hired through the Intel grant at CSU for three years to support the Intel-funded project, which aims to train CSU students in semiconductor technology through a new certificate program in semiconductor processing and a minor program in computer hardware technology and establishing microfabrication and simulation labs at CSU. Dr. Khan has a Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering from the University of Toledo and was a postdoctoral Research Associate at North Carolina Agricultural and Technical State University, where they gained valuable experience in cognitive radios, genetic algorithms, fuzzy logic, machine learning, and operationalizing autonomy.<br />As a Research Assistant Professor of Electronic Engineering Technology, Dr. Khan will bring their expertise to the project and help drive innovation in the semiconductor industry. The CSU Intel team is excited to work with Dr. Khan and leverage their knowledge and expertise to achieve their goals.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Powerex visit to CSU</title><dc:subject>Blog</dc:subject><dc:date>2023-01-31T14:09:00-05:00</dc:date><link>https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Powerex.html#unique-entry-id-8</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Powerex.html#unique-entry-id-8</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-size:14px; ">On Tuesday, January 31, the Powerex team, consisting of Dr. Scott Leslie (Chief Technologist), Garold Mobley (Project Manager &ndash; CHIPs ACT), Jeremy J. Shaffer (Senior Sales Engineer &ndash; Consultant), Donnie Voland (Semiconductor Process Engineer), visited CSU to explore potential collaboration opportunities and partnerships for the CHIPS Act Innovation/Training Hub/Center. The visit was an opportunity to discuss areas of mutual interest, including educational and training programs for workforce development in the semiconductor fields.<br />In addition to the Powerex team, Drs. Ganapathy, Amsaad, Ahsan from WSU, and Dr. Chen from Cedarville University joined. The meeting proved to be productive, as the attendees could share their expertise and perspectives on the CHIPS Act and workforce development in semiconductors. It was a successful step toward building stronger partnerships and collaborations between CSU, university partners, and the industry.<br /></span></p><p style="text-align:center;"><img class="imageStyle" alt="powerex" src="https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/powerex.jpg" width="888" height="666" /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Central State University joined Midwest Semiconductor Network</title><dc:subject>Blog</dc:subject><dc:date>2023-01-05T15:30:48-05:00</dc:date><link>https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/MSN.html#unique-entry-id-7</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/MSN.html#unique-entry-id-7</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="imageStyle" alt="semiconductors" src="https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/semiconductors.jpg" width="480" height="320" /><span style="font-size:14px; "><br /></span></p><p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-size:14px; ">CSU recently joined </span><span style="font-size:14px; "><a href="https://erik.osu.edu/mw-sc-network" target="_blank">Midwest Semiconductor Network</a></span><span style="font-size:14px; ">, a network from a group of leading research institutions from Ohio, Michigan, Illinois, and Indiana, to support the semiconductor and microelectronics industries and address their research and workforce needs in Ohio.</span></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Open Position for Assistant Professor of Electronic Engineering</title><dc:subject>Blog</dc:subject><dc:date>2022-10-27T18:53:36-04:00</dc:date><link>https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Assistant_Professor_Electronic_Engineering.html#unique-entry-id-6</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Assistant_Professor_Electronic_Engineering.html#unique-entry-id-6</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:justify;"><span style="font-size:14px; ">Research Assistant Professor of Electronic Engineering Technology<br />Application deadline: 11/30/2022<br />Details and Applications: </span><span style="font-size:14px; "><a href="https://careers.centralstate.edu/postings/6405" target="_blank">https://careers.centralstate.edu/postings/6405</a></span><span style="font-size:14px; "><br /><br />Central State University (Wilberforce, Ohio) is seeking a highly motivated individual for a full-time, 3-year, non-tenure-track Research Assistant Professor of Electronic Engineering Technology position beginning January 2023. The position is in the broad areas of semiconductor materials and devices. The successful candidate is expected to develop an independent and externally funded research program that involves undergraduate students, teach new and existing courses, and work to advance diversity, equity, and inclusion in the semiconductor field. CSU values the diversity of faculty and staff and encourages applicants from diverse backgrounds to apply. For full consideration, application packages should be submitted by November 30th, 2022, through the CSU careers website: </span><span style="font-size:14px; "><a href="https://careers.centralstate.edu/postings/6405" target="_blank">https://careers.centralstate.edu/postings/6405</a></span><span style="font-size:14px; ">. Review of applications will begin immediately and continue until the position is filled. For any inquiries regarding this position, please contact Dr. Mahmoud A. Abdallah (</span><span style="font-size:14px; "><a href="https://intel-csu.github.io/" target="_blank">mabdallah@centralstate.edu</a></span><span style="font-size:14px; ">).<br /></span></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>WSU cleanroom labs visit</title><dc:subject>Blog</dc:subject><dc:date>2022-09-29T01:01:53-04:00</dc:date><link>https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/WSU_cleanroom_visit_Sep29_2022.html#unique-entry-id-3</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/WSU_cleanroom_visit_Sep29_2022.html#unique-entry-id-3</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><span style="font-size:14px; ">WSU cleanroom labs visit on Sep. 29, 2022.<br /></span><img class="imageStyle" alt="image001" src="https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/WSU.jpg" width="799" height="600" /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>WYSO Interview; Sep. 26&#x2c; 2022</title><dc:subject>Blog</dc:subject><dc:date>2022-09-26T10:34:10-04:00</dc:date><link>https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/WYSO_Sep26_2022.html#unique-entry-id-4</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/WYSO_Sep26_2022.html#unique-entry-id-4</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="imageStyle" alt="WYSO" src="https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/wyso-2.png" width="458" height="110" /><br /><span style="font-size:14px; color:#0C0D14;font-weight:bold; "><br /></span></p><p style="text-align:left;"><span style="font-size:14px; color:#0C0D14;font-weight:bold; ">WYSO:</span><span style="font-size:14px; color:#0C0D14;"> CSU Semiconductor Program:&nbsp;Central State University will partner with 5 other colleges and universities, and Intel, to create a new semiconductor education program. It will focus on teaching and training minority students to become the technicians and engineers who will work at the new Intel semiconductor plant. The program will start in Fall 2023. More at<br /></span><span style="font-size:14px; color:#3954D8;"><u><a href="https://www.wyso.org/local-and-statewide-news/2022-09-26/wyso-morning-news-update-september-26-2022">https://www.wyso.org/local-and-statewide-news/2022-09-26/wyso-morning-news-update-september-26-2022</a></u></span><span style="font:12px Times-Roman; color:#0C0D14;"><br /></span></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Intel Kickoff event</title><dc:subject>Blog</dc:subject><dc:date>2022-09-23T00:54:19-04:00</dc:date><link>https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Intel_Kickoff_event_Sep23_2022.html#unique-entry-id-2</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Intel_Kickoff_event_Sep23_2022.html#unique-entry-id-2</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<span style="font-size:14px; color:#000000;">Intel kickoff event at CSCC, Sep. 23, 2022:<br /></span><span style="font-size:14px; ">L2R: Fathi Amsaad (WSU), Gabriela Cruz Thompson (Intel), Subhashini Ganapathy (WSU), Steven Bibyk (OSU), Steven Ringel (OSU), Mahmoud A. Abdallah (CSU), Xiaowei Chen (Cedarville Univ.), Margery Coulson-Clark (CSU), Mohammadreza Hadizadeh (CSU), Abayomi J. Ajayi-Majebi (CSU).<br /></span><p style="text-align:center;"><img class="imageStyle" alt="Sep23_1_2" src="https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Intel_Kickoff.jpg" width="840" height="369" /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Intel visit to CSU campus</title><dc:subject>Blog</dc:subject><dc:date>2022-09-20T00:43:00-04:00</dc:date><link>https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Intel_visit_Sep22_2022.html#unique-entry-id-1</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Intel_visit_Sep22_2022.html#unique-entry-id-1</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<span style="font-size:14px; color:#000000;">Melinda Murdock (University Relations Manager, Intel Corp.) and Pia Wilson-Body (President of Intel Foundation) </span><span style="font-size:14px; ">visited the CSU campus on September 20, 2022.<br /></span><p style="text-align:center;"><img class="imageStyle" alt="20220920_102526" src="https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/visit_Sep20_2022.jpg" width="826" height="620" /></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>CSU Press Release</title><dc:subject>Blog</dc:subject><dc:date>2022-09-09T11:41:53-04:00</dc:date><link>https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/CSU_PR_Sep9_2022.html#unique-entry-id-5</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/CSU_PR_Sep9_2022.html#unique-entry-id-5</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align:center;"><img class="imageStyle" alt="PR" src="https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Press_Release.png" width="1360" height="1172" /><br /><br /></p><p style="text-align:left;"><span style="color:#000000;">Contact: Debbie Alberico, Public Relations Director<br /></span><span style="color:#0B4CB3;"><u><a href="mailto:dalberico@centralstate.edu">dalberico@centralstate.edu</a></u></span><span style="color:#000000;"><br />937-376-6605</span><span style="font-size:14px; color:#000000;"><br />&nbsp;<br /></span><span style="font-size:14px; color:#000000;font-weight:bold; ">Immediate Release</span><span style="font-size:14px; color:#000000;"><br />&nbsp;<br /></span><span style="color:#000000;">September 9, 2022</span><span style="font-size:14px; color:#000000;"><br />&nbsp;<br />Central State University&rsquo;s partnership is poised to provide new employment for students<br />&nbsp;<br />The groundbreaking celebration for the new Intel facility in Columbus, Ohio, was today at 10:00 a.m. Officials from the private and public sectors were on hand to share in welcoming the high-tech industry.<br />&nbsp;<br />United States President Joe Biden was on the stage to applaud the efforts of Intel and other partners who made the Chips Act a reality. He recognized Central State University alum U.S. Congresswoman Joyce Beatty, who stated, &ldquo;This is a big day for a little black girl from Ohio who got a chance to ride on Air Force One.&rdquo; &ldquo;This is a day for us to celebrate one month ago on August 9,&rdquo; she commented. &ldquo;The president signing the Chips Act into law and turning this into, as they say, the Silicon Heartland,&rdquo; Beatty added. <br />&nbsp;<br />Biden said of Beatty, &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t think we could have gotten the Infrastructure Bill done without Joyce. &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know what you did in those last four hours, but you got it done,&rdquo; he added.<br />&nbsp;<br /></span><span style="font-size:14px; color:#000000;">Ohio colleges like Central State University, Ohio&rsquo;s only publicly funded Historically Black College and Universities, are ready for their share of 50 million dollars in partnerships with Intel and the federal government, to help develop students who can work at Intel. <br />CSU Provost Dr. F. Erik Brooks said, &ldquo;We are proud of CSU&rsquo;s Faculty and staff&rsquo;s efforts in creating a new program in collaboration with other colleges and universities across Ohio that addresses Intel&rsquo;s need and provides meaningful employment opportunities for our students.&rdquo;<br />Intel announced the first phase of funding for its Ohio Semiconductor Education and Research Program. A recent Intel press release said, &ldquo;during this first phase, Intel is providing 17.7 million dollars for eight proposals from leading institutions and collaborators in Ohio to develop semiconductor-focused education and workforce programs.&rdquo; <br />&ldquo;The Intel Semiconductor Education Program at Central State University is our journey to promote diversity in the semiconductor field by creating a pipeline to provide practical learning experiences in semiconductor fabrication techniques and processes for underrepresented students and preparing them for Intel careers,&rdquo; said Mohammadreza Hadizadeh, Central State University Associate Professor of Physics. &ldquo;We are so excited to receive this award and work with Intel and our collaborators to train our students and develop a new phase of our education and research in semiconductor manufacturing,&rdquo; he added.<br />&ldquo;As the only public Historically Black University in Ohio, Central State University has an obligation to produce highly qualified graduates with the knowledge and skills necessary to ensure that the United States maintains its leading scientific and innovative edge in the global economy.&rdquo; &ldquo;CSU is excited to work with Intel as a higher educational partner to create a diversified workforce that represents the full spectrum of the United States.&rdquo; &ldquo;Central State and our collaborative partners including Columbus State Community College, The Ohio State University, Clark State Community College, and Wright State University will create a pipeline that produces underrepresented students prepared for Intel careers by giving students knowledge and practical experience in semi-conductor fabrication techniques, processes, and equipment by establishing a semiconductor educational program at CSU,&rdquo; said University President Dr. Jack Thomas.<br />&ldquo;Central State offers Intel a unique opportunity to partner with an institution of higher education with a demonstrated record of producing highly qualified underrepresented graduates in manufacturing engineering and other fields necessary to meet Intel&rsquo;s workforce demands,&rdquo; stated Morakinyo A.O. Kuti, Ph.D., Interim Dean, John W. Garland College of Engineering, Science, Technology, and Agriculture and Director of the 1890 Land-Grant Programs.<br />&ldquo;The Industrial Midwest is back! It was exciting to be in the Silicon Heartland at Intel&rsquo;s groundbreaking with local, state, and national leaders. President Biden recognized Central State University for our partnership with Intel and CSU alum, Congresswoman Joyce Beatty, for her significant contribution to the Chips Act,&rsquo;&rsquo; exclaimed Thomas. </span></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title>Intel visit to CSU campus</title><dc:subject>Blog</dc:subject><dc:date>2022-09-08T00:15:02-04:00</dc:date><link>https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Intel_visit_Sep8_2022.html#unique-entry-id-0</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/Intel_visit_Sep8_2022.html#unique-entry-id-0</guid><content:encoded><![CDATA[<span style="font-size:14px; ">Gabriela Cruz Thompson, the Director of University Research Collaboration in Intel Labs, Intel Corp, visited the CSU campus on September 8, 2022.</span><br /><p style="text-align:center;"><img class="imageStyle" alt="2022-09-08_Dr.GabrielaCruzThompson" src="https://intel-csu.github.io/blog/files/2022-09-08_dr.gabrielacruzthompson.jpg" width="807" height="605" /></p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel>
</rss>